<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>whatever on 6510</title>
    <link>http://6510.nu/categories/whatever/</link>
    <description>Recent content in whatever on 6510</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Kristoffer Gr&amp;ouml;nlund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 13:44:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://6510.nu/categories/whatever/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Rook</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/rook-at-openinfra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 13:44:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/rook-at-openinfra/</guid>
      <description>The other day I presented Rook and Ceph at OpenInfra Forum #8 in Stockholm.
I was told that there&amp;rsquo;s going to be video published of the talk eventually, but here are the slides as PDF for anyone who might be interested, and there&amp;rsquo;s a web version here.
I used reveal.js to make the presentation, if you are interested you can get the sources here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawk API server</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/hawk-apiserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 16:14:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/hawk-apiserver/</guid>
      <description>My relationship with Go so far has been that it&amp;rsquo;s a language that I don&amp;rsquo;t love and don&amp;rsquo;t want to love, but which I find myself being effortlessly productive in, in a way that I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced with a lot of other languages unless I have years of experience with them.
The Hawk API server is an example of that. For the HA stack, we had been using lighttpd as the web server for Hawk, the web frontend for the HA cluster stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koi</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/koi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 19:28:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/koi/</guid>
      <description>Koi is a self-contained cluster management software package, written in C++. The main purpose of koi is to maintain a small cluster of machines (usually 3 or 5) where a subset of those machines run services. Services usually consist of a set of bash scripts that start, stop and monitor some other piece of software. This software only runs in active mode on one of the machines, with the other nodes functioning as backup servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roam</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:27:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/roam/</guid>
      <description>Here, at the very last day of 2019, I thought I should start a series of posts documenting some of the hobby projects I&amp;rsquo;ve created through the years. Most of them can be found on github, at least the ones that are in source code form.
R O A M was a Hackweek project at SUSE, in which I wanted to implement a basic Minecraft-style landscape renderer in C. Source code available at github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s LISP like it&#39;s 1959 (Rev. II)</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/fossnorth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 10:32:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/fossnorth/</guid>
      <description>FOSS North, 2019. Second revision of this talk.
It&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the same talk as at LCA, in part because I am terrible at sticking to a script but also because I rewrote at least half of the presentation, expanding on some parts and trying to actually get to the part where I implement a lisp interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s LISP like it&#39;s 1959</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/1959/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:32:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/1959/</guid>
      <description>Presentation I did at linux.conf.au 2019 about the history of Lisp, computers and programming in general.
Got written up as an article on LWN.net to my delight, and so far the comments have generally been surprisingly positive pretty much everywhere.
On April 7 (2019), I will be doing an updated version of this talk at FOSS North in Gothenburg - my time slot is 15 minutes longer, so I might actually get through most of the talk this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone gets a pony!</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/pony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 08:22:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/pony/</guid>
      <description>Presentation I did at linux.conf.au 2018 about the programming language Pony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clusterlabs Summit 2017</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/clusterlabs-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 16:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/clusterlabs-summit/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, I organized a conference for the first and only time. This was the Clusterlabs semi-regular developer conference for the Linux HA / Clusterlabs community. It was generally a success, attended by people from various companies and places, and surprisingly not a terrible amount of work to arrange. This despite the fact that the conference was held in Nuremberg, Germany while I live in Sweden and work remotely.
There is a really nice write-up of the conference by Tanja from SUSE here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Managers #lca2017</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/lca2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 09:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/lca2017/</guid>
      <description>.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }
edit: This got written up as an article on LWN.net, a huge thank you to Jonathan Corbet for that!
I have also been thinking about this presentation a lot in the years following - the package management problem remains unsolved and it&amp;rsquo;s still something I wrestle with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiding in the Shadow of Neptune</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/neptune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 19:05:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/neptune/</guid>
      <description>.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawk 2.0 and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/osc16-hawk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 15:34:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/osc16-hawk/</guid>
      <description>This presentation was given at openSUSEconf 2016 in Nuremberg, Germany.
In it, I presented Hawk 2.0, demonstrating how to set up a live cluster and showing off some of the new features in the second major release.
Around this time I also created a website for Hawk which unfortunately (as of January 2020) hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since: https://hawk-ui.github.io/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Rust and the OBS</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/rust-obs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 15:44:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/rust-obs/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 I was involved in packaging the rust compiler for openSUSE, and this presentation describes some of the hurdles I encountered on the way. It is also a very basic introduction to the rust language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring History with Hawk</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/osc15-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 15:40:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/osc15-history/</guid>
      <description>Hawk is a web frontend for the ClusterLabs HA stack.
This is a presentation of the History Explorer feature which I did at openSUSEconf 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>