<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>6510</title>
    <link>http://6510.nu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 6510</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Kristoffer Gr&amp;ouml;nlund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 19:28:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://6510.nu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Koi</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/koi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 19:28:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/koi/</guid>
      <description>Koi is a self-contained cluster management software package, written in C++. The main purpose of koi is to maintain a small cluster of machines (usually 3 or 5) where a subset of those machines run services. Services usually consist of a set of bash scripts that start, stop and monitor some other piece of software. This software only runs in active mode on one of the machines, with the other nodes functioning as backup servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roam</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:27:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/roam/</guid>
      <description>Here, at the very last day of 2019, I thought I should start a series of posts documenting some of the hobby projects I&#39;ve created through the years. Most of them can be found on github, at least the ones that are in source code form.
R O A M was a Hackweek project at SUSE, in which I wanted to implement a basic Minecraft-style landscape renderer in C. Source code available at github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s LISP like it&#39;s 1959 (Rev. II)</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/fossnorth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 10:32:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/fossnorth/</guid>
      <description>FOSS North, 2019. Second revision of this talk.
It&#39;s not exactly the same talk as at LCA, in part because I am terrible at sticking to a script but also because I rewrote at least half of the presentation, expanding on some parts and trying to actually get to the part where I implement a lisp interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s LISP like it&#39;s 1959</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/1959/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:32:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/1959/</guid>
      <description>Presentation I did at linux.conf.au 2019 about the history of Lisp, computers and programming in general.
Got written up as an article on LWN.net to my delight, and so far the comments have generally been surprisingly positive pretty much everywhere.
On April 7 (2019), I will be doing an updated version of this talk at FOSS North in Gothenburg - my time slot is 15 minutes longer, so I might actually get through most of the talk this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone gets a pony!</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/pony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 08:22:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/pony/</guid>
      <description>Presentation I did at linux.conf.au 2018 about the programming language Pony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Managers #lca2017</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/lca2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 09:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/lca2017/</guid>
      <description>.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; } edit: This got written up as an article on LWN.net, a huge thank you to Jonathan Corbet for that!
I have also been thinking about this presentation a lot in the years following - the package management problem remains unsolved and it&#39;s still something I wrestle with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiding in the Shadow of Neptune</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/neptune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 19:05:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/neptune/</guid>
      <description>.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; } </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 20:14:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the personal website of Kristoffer Grönlund. I like making things. I&#39;m a software developer by day, so a lot of what I make is in the form of source code. I also make music, art and houses - and possibly other things.
I&#39;m not sure exactly what my idea behind this site is. Once, having a personal website was an essential part of the web experience. These days it seems less relevant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>