<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presentation on 6510</title>
    <link>http://6510.nu/tags/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presentation on 6510</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Kristoffer Gr&amp;ouml;nlund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 16:05:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://6510.nu/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clusterlabs Summit 2017</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/clusterlabs-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 16:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/clusterlabs-summit/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, I organized a conference for the first and only time. This was the Clusterlabs semi-regular developer conference for the Linux HA / Clusterlabs community. It was generally a success, attended by people from various companies and places, and surprisingly not a terrible amount of work to arrange. This despite the fact that the conference was held in Nuremberg, Germany while I live in Sweden and work remotely.
There is a really nice write-up of the conference by Tanja from SUSE here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawk 2.0 and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/osc16-hawk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 15:34:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/osc16-hawk/</guid>
      <description>This presentation was given at openSUSEconf 2016 in Nuremberg, Germany.
In it, I presented Hawk 2.0, demonstrating how to set up a live cluster and showing off some of the new features in the second major release.
Around this time I also created a website for Hawk which unfortunately (as of January 2020) hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since: https://hawk-ui.github.io/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Rust and the OBS</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/rust-obs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 15:44:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/rust-obs/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 I was involved in packaging the rust compiler for openSUSE, and this presentation describes some of the hurdles I encountered on the way. It is also a very basic introduction to the rust language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring History with Hawk</title>
      <link>http://6510.nu/osc15-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 15:40:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://6510.nu/osc15-history/</guid>
      <description>Hawk is a web frontend for the ClusterLabs HA stack.
This is a presentation of the History Explorer feature which I did at openSUSEconf 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>